<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Juliana&#39;s Water Data Nerd Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Juliana&#39;s Water Data Nerd Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>juliana.spector@water.ca.gov (Juliana Spector)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>juliana.spector@water.ca.gov (Juliana Spector)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Web scraping from web pages in batch</title>
      <link>/post/web-scraping-from-webpages-in-batch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>juliana.spector@water.ca.gov (Juliana Spector)</author>
      <guid>/post/web-scraping-from-webpages-in-batch/</guid>
      <description>Why use web scraping?If you find that you often need to visit similar web pages and extract the same information from each page, web scraping can be a useful strategy to save time and increase efficiency. As part of my job duties, I am responsible for checking water well driller license expiration dates on Contractors State License Board website monthly. There are over 1000 active licenses that need to be tracked for the state; to check expiration dates, I need to navigate to a separate web page for each license, which can be cumbersome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring and listening to webhook using Box Developer and Google Sheets</title>
      <link>/post/2020-08-14-webhook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>juliana.spector@water.ca.gov (Juliana Spector)</author>
      <guid>/post/2020-08-14-webhook/</guid>
      <description>What is a webhook?Webhooks are user-defined HTTP callbacks that are triggered by some event, such as pushing code to a repository or a comment being posted to a blog. When that event occurs, the source site makes an HTTP request to the URL configured for the webhook. In my case, I wanted to enable a callback when a file was uploaded to a Box folder owned by my organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>juliana.spector@water.ca.gov (Juliana Spector)</author>
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>I am an Engineering Geologist at the Department of Water Resources based in Sacramento, California. Outside of work, I enjoy singing in choir, rock climbing, and backpacking in the Sierras.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>